James Settles

Data Scientist | Los Angeles, CA • <u>settles.james.b@gmail.com</u> • (540) 479-7087 Linkedin: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/james-bryce-settles-99675013a/</u> Portfolio Site: https://eyefixcode.github.io/ | GitHub: https://github.com/eyefixcode

SUMMARY

Deeply committed to finding new ways to use data to support health promotion and equity. My tech stack proficiencies include Python, SQL, R, SPSS, SAS, and leveraging business intelligence platforms such as Microsoft Power BI.

With 4 years of data analysis expertise, I offer a diverse background with a successful track record of deploying data mining studies, constructing database queries, performing statistical modeling, and curating cloud-based dashboards hosting KPI's.

I am eager to utilize my skillset towards initiatives that share the same commitment to making positive impacts on public health and health disparity reduction.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

(Feb 2022 – Jan 2023) Curative Inc. — Systems Engineer (Systems Engineering)

- o Routinely developed business intelligence dashboards assessing lab test Turn-Around-Time, positivity rates, and site-based clinical information.
- o Analyzed public disease data to inform lab expansion for COVID-19 and Monkeypox.
- o Constructed SQL queries for stakeholders upholding HIPAA compliance.
- o Developed agent-based model to visualize staffing needs and calculate FTEs.

(Nov 2019 – Feb 2022) ThermoFisher Scientific — Scientist, Automation Specialist (Vaccine Sciences)

- Developed dashboards using Power BI with advanced DAX functions, integrating data from ODBC, Salesforce, and various static file formats (.csv, .txt, .xls) for Finance, Automation, and Clinical Lab teams.
- o Built automated approval workflow via PowerAutomate script and Sharepoint database.
- Executed data-mining project via python to query lab automated instrument utilization efficiency, and then compiled data into SQLite database.
- o Constructed SQL queries from LIMS database.
- o Developed VBA excel macros to increase efficiency in sample storage procedures.
- Validated Python and SQL scripts for clinical use upholding the standard software version control practices.

(Jan 2019 – Jun 2019) VCU — Research Assistant (Urban Ecology)

- o In Capstone, collaborated with local researchers to design a longitudinal observational study in Richmond, Virginia to analyze variation in local air quality.
- o Deployed 8 portable air quality devices that measured particulate matter (PM $\leq 2.5 \mu m$).
- Eanes, Andre & Lookingbill, Todd & Hoffman, Jeremy & Saverino, Kelly & Fong, Stephen.
 (2020). Assessing Inequitable Urban Heat Islands and Air Pollution Disparities with Low-Cost Sensors in Richmond, Virginia. Sustainability. 12. 10089.
 10.3390/su122310089.

James Settles

Data Scientist | Los Angeles, CA • <u>settles.james.b@gmail.com</u> • (540) 479-7087 Linkedin: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/james-bryce-settles-99675013a/</u> Portfolio Site: https://eyefixcode.github.io/ | GitHub: https://github.com/eyefixcode

EDUCATION

(In-progress) University of Southern California (Keck School of Medicine) – Master's in

Public Health (MPH)

• GPA: 3.75

Concentration: Biostatistics and Epidemiology

(May 2019) Virginia Commonwealth University - Bachelor of Science (BS) in Biology

Minor in Chemistry

CORE COMPETENCIES

Python MS Office (Excel VBA Macros) Windows CMD/.Batch

R/R-Shiny Microsoft Power BI MacOS .Bash

SQL (SSMS/Oracle/SQLite) Microsoft Power Automate GitHub SPSS Microsoft SharePoint Git

SAS PostMan API

AWARDS

PPD Inc. part of ThermoFisher Scientific

(*Feb 2021*) Moderna team award recipient for exceptional performance in the automation of assay development, validation, and production to expedite the rate of assessing COVID-19 vaccine efficacy clinical trials for SARS-COV-2/Omicron variants.

ORGANIZATIONS

(Jun 2022 – Present) Society for Laboratory Automation and Screening (SLAS) (Jan 2023 – Dec 2024) American Society for Microbiology (ASM)

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

(May 2021) **HAMILTON Company** – Venus Software Development Training

VOLUNTEER WORK

VCU MCV Hospital

(May 2017 – Aug 2017) Surgical Trauma ICU Assistant

(Jan 2019 – Jun 2019) Massey Cancer Center Library Assistant

Mary Washington Hospital

(May 2016 – Aug 2016) Orthopedic Surgery Physical Therapy Assistant

VCU Office of Sustainability

(Jan 2016 – Jun 2016) VCU Campus Garden and Green Wall Construction